[ Cheering ]
[欢呼声]
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Hello, everyone.
&gt;&gt; 大家好
Welcome to Engineering for
欢迎大家
Testability.
来到可测试性工程学讲座
My name is Brian Croom, and I
我是 Brian Croom
work on the Xcode Team.
现在在 Xcode 团队工作
My colleague Greg and I, want to
我和我的同事 Greg
share some things that we've
想要和大家分享一下
been learning about testability
我们对于可测试性的学习成果
and what it means for the
以及可测试性在
process of developing great
开发出色 app 进程中
apps.
起到的重要作用
I'll start by talking about what
首先 我想要讲一讲
it means for an app's code to be
一个 app 的代码具有可测试性
testable.
究竟是什么意思
And we'll see some examples of
我们会看到一些实例
techniques that can be applied
看看如何应用技术
to improving testability of an
来提高现有代码
existing code.
的可测试性
Then Gregg will come up, and
然后 Gregg 会和大家探讨
talk about some ways of working
如何使用测试套件
with your test suite to help
来确保
ensure that it helps support the
它能够对你的 app 开发
development of your app, even as
起到协助作用 即使是在
it grows in size and complexity.
开发规模和复杂性不断提高的情况下
So, let's dive in, and talk
好的 我们这就开始
about testability.
首先来谈谈可测试性
I remember a while back, when I
我记得在不久之前
was first learning about writing
我最初开始学习写
tests.
测试
I'd been hearing a lot about how
我已经听说过很多有关
a test suite could help during
测试套件如何能够
the development of my app.
帮助我开发 app 的信息
How it could provide confidence,
测试套件如何能够使我
that the code I was writing was
对正在编写的代码更有把握
working the way it was supposed
能够让其按照期望的方式
to.
运行
How it could help patch
测试套件如何能够帮我
regressions in my code as my app
在 app 不断升级变化的情况下
grew and changed over time.
为代码中的regression打补丁
And how it could serve as
以及如何充当
executable documentation for my
我的代码的
code.
可执行文件
But, I would start writing a
但是 我一开始写测试时
test, and get stuck before I'd
还没有达到这些讨论的范畴
gotten very far.
就陷入停滞无法继续编写下去了
It felt as if my app's code were
感觉好像我的 app 代码
actively trying to prevent me
主动地抗拒我
from writing the test.
写测试
It took a while, but eventually
这个情况持续了一段时间
I discovered that I was
不过最后我发现
structuring my code in a way
我构建代码的方式
that interfered with effective
阻碍了
testing.
我进行有效的测试
To explore what this means,
为了搞清楚这是什么意思
let's first take a look at a
首先请大家看这个单元测试
unit test for some code that is
这个单元测试的对象是
readily testable, sorting an
已经具有可测试性的代码
array.
该代码是用来进行数组排序的
This is a test that exercises
这个测试使用的是
the Sorted Method from the Swift
Swift Standard Library 中的
Standard Library.
Sorted Method
It begins by setting up an array
首先它创建一组
of unsorted values.
未经排序的数值
It calls the sorted method on
然后它为这组数值
that array.
调用 Sorted Method
And then asserts that the
然后再判断
returned array has the values in
返回的数组中数值按照预期的
the expected order.
顺序排列
Generalizing this, we can see
概括说来 我们能够看到
that the test structure consists
该测试的结构由三部分组成
of first, setting up any
第一 创建任何
required input state or values,
所需的输入状态或数值
then, calling the code being
然后 调用被测试的代码
tested, and finally, asserting
最后 判断
that the returned output is
返回的输出信息
correct.
是正确的
This is sometimes referred to as
有些情况下 这个模式被称作
the Arrange Act Assert Pattern.
3A 模式（Arrange Act Assert）
So, we've seen that sorted is a
我们已经看过了
nicely testable piece of code.
这个具有不错可测试性的排序代码
But I know what you're thinking,
不过 我知道你们现在在想
"My app's code doesn't have a
我的 app 代码里
single sorting algorithm in it."
没有一点排序算法啊
In my experience, most of the
就我的经验而言 app 里面的
code in apps, looks pretty
大多数代码
different than the sorting
确实都和排序算法有
algorithm.
天差地别
Still, there are some
不过 我们还是可以
characteristics of the sorted
在我们的 app 中努力
method that we can strive to
实现一些 Sorted Method 的
achieve in our app's code, and
特性
to make them more testable.
以使其更加具有可测试性
Specifically, testable code
更确切地说 具有可测试性的代码
provides a way for its clients
能够帮助其客户端
to have control over all of the
对代码处理的所有 inputs
inputs that it operates on.
进行完全控制
It provides a way for its
它能够帮助用户端
clients to inspect any output
检查所有
being generated.
正在生成的 output
And it avoids relying on
它避免了完全依赖于
internal state that could affect
内部状态的情况 而这种情况
the code's behavior later on.
有可能在日后影响到代码的行为
I want to use code examples to
我想要举一些关于代码的例子
demonstrate a couple of
来向大家展示几种技术
techniques that can be used to
这些技术可以用来把
help application code take on
这些特性赋予给应用程序的代码
these characteristics, and thus,
并借此
improve its testability.
提高其可测试性
The first technique is how to
第一个技术是
introduce protocols and
如何将 protocols 及
parameterization into a piece of
parameterization 引进到
code.
一个代码中
For this example, imagine a
比如 想象这是一个文档浏览的 app
document browser app, that is
能够对
capable of previewing documents
各种不同类型的文档
of various types, and has the
进行预览
ability to switch to a different
也可以切换到另一个不同的 app 里
app for viewing it in more
进行更加细致的查看
detail or editing it.
或者编辑
The previous screen we see here,
我们看到的前一个画面
includes an open button for
包括一个打开按钮
this, along with a segmented
还有一个分段控制
control for choosing [inaudible]
用来选择
open for viewing or editing.
是进行查看还是进行编辑
So, let's have a look at the
好的 我们先来看看
first try at some code for this
这一界面
screen.
背后的代码
So, the event handler in the
当打开按钮被按下时
view controller that gets
view controller 中的
invoked when that Open button is
event handler
tapped.
被调用
It starts with some business
首先是一些 business logic
logic for constructing a URL to
用来构建一个 URL
be used to request that iOS
这个 URL 被用来请求 iOS
switch to the other app.
切换到其它 app
Then, it uses the shared UI
然后 它使用由
application instance, provided
UIKit 提供的
by UIKit, to determine whether
shared UI application instance
the system is able to handle
来确定系统是否能够处理
this Open request, and perform
这个打开的请求 如果可以的话
the open URL action if it is.
则执行这个打开 URL 的动作
And if not, it calls a helper
如果不可以的话 则调用辅助方式
method to show some UI to direct
显示一些 UI 来引导
the user to install the other
用户去安装另一个
app.
app
Now, I want to write some tests
现在 我想要写一些测试
to make sure that this Open
来确保这个打开按钮
button is working the way it's
能够以我们期望的方式
supposed to.
运行
There are a couple of different
测试这一点
ways to approach testing this.
有许多种不同的途径
One option would be to write a
一种方式就是写一个
UI test.
UI 测试
We ask to launch the app,
我们要求启动 app
navigate to this screen, tap on
导航到这一屏
the [inaudible] control, to peck
点击控制键
and open mode, tap the Open
轻击 open mode
button, and then verify that the
点击打开按钮
phone switched to show the other
然后验证手机切换显示
app.
另一个 app
While this would work, there are
虽然这个办法行得通
some drawbacks to this approach.
但是也有些缺点
For one, the task would probably
比如 它运行时间
take a while to run, especially
可能会比较长
if I wanted to expand it to test
特别是当我想要对测试内容进行拓展时
with several different documents
比如测试不同种类文档
types for the different open
在不同打开模式下
modes.
的运行效果
The bigger problem, however, is
更严重的缺点是
that a UI test would have no way
一个 UI 测试无论如何都无法
to inspect that URL that was
检查刚刚被生成的
being generated, to request that
用来请求 iOS 切换 app
iOS switch apps.
的 URL
And that URL is really something
而那个 URL 则是
that I want to be able to
我真正想要
inspect more precisely.
进行更加精准检查的对象
So, it really feels like a unit
所以 似乎
test is more appropriate for the
单元测试是更加
situation.
适合这种情况的
So, let's see what it would take
我们就来看看
to write a unit test for this
要为这个代码写一个
code.
单元测试需要些什么
First, you need an instance of
首先 你需要一个 view controller
the view controller to work
的 instance
with.
来进行操作
My view controller uses a
我的 view controller 为其 UI
storyboard for its UI, so I'll
使用了一个 storyboard
ask UI Storyboard to give me an
所以我会让 UI Storyboard 来
instance of the view controller.
提供给我一个 view controller 的 instance
Then we need to load the view to
然后我们需要加载这个视图
populate that [inaudible]
来填入控制属性
control property, so that we --
这样
it's populated by the view data.
它就被视图数据填充了
We can then configure that for
然后可以依据我们的 open mode
our open mode.
对其进行配置
Provide a document to work with.
提供一个可供处理的文档
And with the setup finally
设定最终完成之后
complete, we're now ready to
我们现在就可以
call the method being tested.
调用要被测试的 method 了
But what do we do now?
但是我们现在该怎么做呢
It's not so clear what kind of
我们能够在这里写哪一种
assertion we could write here.
assertion 似乎不太明了
Let's go back to the code, and
我们先回到代码那里
look more closely at what makes
再仔细看看究竟是什么
this challenging to test.
导致了我们在进行测试时遇到这样的挑战
For one thing, just being in a
首先 单单是因为在 view controller 内
view controller, made the
的这个情况
methods test more complicated.
就使得 methods 测试更加复杂了
You're going to jump through
为了得到可以进行操作的
some hoops to get the view
view controller instance
controller instance to work
你就必须要
with.
越过重重关卡
Then here, we're pulling input
在这里 我们是从视图中直接
state directly from the view.
取出 input 状态
[Inaudible] of the test had to
测试不得不强制
force the view to load, and then
加载该视图
indirectly provide the input by
然后再间接地通过在
setting a property on some
一些 sub-view 上设置一个属性来
sub-view.
提供 input
The biggest problem though was
不过 最严重的问题
this usage of a UI application
是这个 UI application shared instance
shared instance.
的使用
The return value from this call
这个 canOpenURL 的回传值
to can open URL, is effectively
实际上
another input for the method.
是该 method 的另一个 input
But since this relies on global
但是因为这个是依赖于
system state, there's no
全局系统状态的
programmatic way for the test to
我们并无法给测试提供程序化的方法
control the result of this
来控制这个 query
query.
的结果
Nor is there a good way for a
对于一个单元测试而言
unit test to observe the side
也没有一个好的方式能够观察
effects of opening a URL.
打开一个 URL 的副效应
In fact, after calling this, the
实际上 在调用这个之后
test render app would actually
测试渲染的 app
be sent to the background, and
会被送至后台
there'd be no way to bring it
之后就再也没有办法
back to the foreground
把它带回到
afterwards.
前台了
So, let's see what we can do to
那么 我们就来看看
improve the testability of this
我们能够做些什么来提升
code.
这个代码的可测试性
We can start by getting it out
首先我们可以将其从
of the view controller.
view controller 中取出来
Let's introduce a new document
然后引入一个新的
opener class, to encapsulate
document opener 类 将
this logic and behavior.
这个 logic 和 behavior 封装起来
The open mode and document
现在应该为 Open mode
inputs, should now be provided a
和 document inputs
simple method arguments that the
提供一个简单的 method arguments
test can pass indirectly.
这样测试就可以间接地通过
But we still have to fix the
但是 我们仍然需要解决
problems caused by that shared
由 shared UI application incidence
UI application incidence.
引起的问题
What can we do about that?
我们能够怎么做呢
Well, to start, we can stop
首先 我们可以停止
using that [inaudible] accessor
在这里直接
directly into method.
使用 accessor
Let's add an initializer to the
让我们向类中加入
class that lets us pass in a
一个 initializer 这样我们就能够
particular application instance.
得到一个特别的 application instance
We can provide a default value
我们可以为此 argument
for the argument, so the
提供一个初始数值
[inaudible] in the view
这样 在 view controller 中
controller, doesn't have to
就不必要
worry about this detail.
担心这个细节了
Back in the open method, we then
回到 open method 这里
switch over to use the
我们随后切换使用
application instance that was
刚才得到的
passed in.
application instance
Let's see how far this
一起来看看
refactoring gets us.
这个代码重构给我们带来什么效果吧
If we try to rewrite our test
如果我们现在尝试
now, with the document open or
在文档打开或者保持其当前状态的情况下
in its current state, we'll
重写测试
still find ourselves getting
我们会发现自己
stuck.
又被卡住了
You want to pass in an
你想要得到一个
application instance that we
我们能够控制的
have control over.
application instance
So, you can imagine sub-classing
自然 你可以想象将 UI 应用
UI application, overriding the
加入子类别
can open URL and open methods,
覆写这个 canOpenURL 和 open methods
to get the control that we need.
来得到我们想要的控制
However, it turns out that UI
但是 最后的结果是
application strictly enforces
UI 应用严格地遵守其
its singleton nature.
单例本质
And throws an exception to try
引发异常产生例外情况来试图
to make a second instance, even
创造第二个 instance
if it's a subclass.
即使它是一个子类
So, instead of using
所以 为了得到我们想要的控制
sub-classing, to get the control
我们不用加入子类别这个方式
that we need, let's instead add
而是加入一个 protocol
a protocol, URL Opening.
URL Opening
We go to protocol, two methods,
我们看这个 protocol
with precisely the same
和这两个 methods
signatures as the application
它们所用的 signatures
methods that we've been using up
和我们到目前为止的应用 methods 所使用的
to this point.
signatures 一模一样
We still want UI application to
我们仍然想让 UI 应用
be the primary implementation of
成为这个 protocol 的
this protocol.
最主要的实现
So, we'll throw an extension on
然后 我们会给 UI 应用
UI application to give it the
添加一个 extension 来
URL opening conformance.
赋予其 URLOpening 一致性
Since the method signatures line
因为这些方法的 signatures 都
up exactly, you don't have to
正好对应
add any additional code in the
你就不需要再在这个 extension 上
extension to get the
添加额外的代码
conformance.
来达到一致了
With a protocol in place, let's
现在有一个 protocol 已经就绪
update the document opener to
我们就更新 DocumentOpener
use the protocol instead of
来使用这个 protocol
requiring UI application itself.
而不用 UI 应用本身了
First, we change the property
首先 我们来更改其属性
and initialize a parameter to
并初始化参数来接受
accept any implementation of the
这个 URLOpening protocol 的
URL opening protocol.
任何的实现
Note that we're still able to
要注意 我们仍然能够
keep the shared UI application
保持 shard UI application instance 的
instance with the default
默认参数
argument as a convenience when
这样我们之后
we use it in the view
在 view controller 使用它时
controller.
就会方便很多
A final change requires the
最后一个变更需要
document opener simply to adopt
document opener 采用
the URL opener property name.
URL opener 的属性名称
With that, let's return to the
一切都做好了 我们现在回到测试去
test and see how the pieces fit
来一起看看这样操作之后的
together.
效果如何
Since UI Application doesn't
因为 UI 应用不能
give us the control that we need
使我们得到在测试中需要的控制
in our test, we want to create a
我们就想建构
secondary mock implementation of
protocol 的一个
the protocol, to use in its
次级的mock implementation虚拟实现
place.
来在其位置使用
Here we add a sub-implementation
我们在这里已经加上了
of the two methods.
两个 methods 的 sub-implementation
The can open URL method acts as
canOpen URL method 充当
an input from the document
来自 document opener 的
opener.
一个 input
So, the test needs to have
所以 测试需要控制
control over this input.
此 input
We can get that by having the
通过使 implementation 返回
implementation return the value
测试事先设置好的
of a property that the test can
属性的数值
set beforehand.
我们就能够做到这一点
The open method, act as an
而 open method 则充当了
output from the document opener.
来自 document opener 的 output
The test wants to be able to
测试希望能够
access any URL that was passed
接入任何传进这个 method
into this method.
的 URL
We can achieve that by stashing
为了达到这一点 我们可以将
the URL into a property for the
URL 藏到一个属性之中
test to -- to read afterwards.
然后可以让测试在随后读取
So, let's go ahead and write the
好的 我们继续
test.
编写这个测试
First, we create an instance of
首先 我们为刚刚写好的
our mock URL opener that we just
mockURLOpener 创建一个 instance,
wrote, and configure the input
然后用 canOpen 属性
using the can open property.
设置 input
And create a document opener.
创建一个 documentOpener
And we pass in that mock URL
然后将 mock urlOpener 加入
opener as the argument.
作为 argument
With that setup finished, we can
设置好了这个
call the open method, passing in
我们就可以调用 open method
document and open mode values,
加入 document 和 open mode 的数值
to act as the rest of the input.
作为余下的 input
And we can then assert that the
然后 我们可以判断
opened URL property of the mock
mock URLOpener 的
URL opener, has been set to the
openedURL 属性已经设置为
expected URL.
期望的 URL
This one assertion, is testing
这个 assertion 在
both at the open method was
被调用的 open method 和
called at all, as well as the
包含有正确数据的
URL passed in contains the
传入的 URL 上
correct data.
都进行测试
With that test under our belt,
已经学习过这个测试后
you could continue to write
大家就可以继续
tests for other variations of
为其它 input 数据的变体
input data, such as when the can
编写测试了
open property is set to false.
比如 canOpen 属性设置为 false 的变体
But we have a lot more to cover,
我们接下来还有很多内容要讲
so let's just leave it there.
这部分就先讲到这里
So, in this example, you
在这个例子中
performed a few refactorings to
我们进行了一些代码重构
allow us to write unit tests for
以使得我们能够为自己的代码
our code.
编写单元测试
We pulled out explicit
我们抽离掉对一个
references to a shared singleton
shared singleton instance 的
instance, and replaced them with
显示引用
parameterized input to offer
然后用 parameterized input 取代显示引用
substitution.
来作置换
This is sometimes referred to as
一些情况下
a penancy injection.
这个被称作 penancy injection
In this example, we use an
在这个例子中
initializer parameter to achieve
我们使用了一个 initialized parameter
this.
来达到这个目的
We could also have used a
我们也可以使用一个
property setter, or a parameter
属性 setter 或者是
of the method being tested.
接受测试的 method 的一个 parameter
We created a protocol to
我们创建了一个 protocol 来
decouple the code from the
将代码从其先前依赖的
concrete class that it
具体类中
previously depended on.
解耦出来
And we created a test
然后我们又创建了一个
implementation to use in its
测试 implementation 来
place.
在其位置运行
And it gave us the control that
这给予了我们所需的
we needed over the inputs, and
对于 inputs 的控制
the visibility into the outputs.
以及 outputs 的可视性
Next, I want to look at how
接下来 我希望带大家看看
separating out logic from
如何将 logic 从 effects 中分离出来
effects, can also be used to
以及如何用此种操作
enhance testability.
提升可测试性
The example here is an on-disk
这里的例子是一个
cache class, which might be used
OnDiskCache 类
by an app for faster retrieval
可能是被 app 用来
of assets that have been
对先前已经从服务器下载下来的 assets
previously downloaded from a
进行更快速的
server.
取回
This cache defines a script for
该 Cache 界定了
representing the items that it
一个脚本
stores.
此脚本代表了其所储存的条目
It defines the path to the item
它界定了在文件系统中
on the file system, how long
获取该条目的路径
it's been in the cache, and its
以及它在 cache 上存在的时间
size on disk.
和在磁盘上的大小
And it provides a way to get the
并提供了获取
set of all the items currently
目前所有储存在 cache 上条目集合
stored in the cache.
的方法
The method that you want to look
现在需要注意的 method
at now, though, is a cleanup
是一个
method.
cleanup method
It's meant to be called
这个 method 应该是被
periodically, to ensure that the
周期性地调用
cache doesn't grow to take up
以保证 cache 不会增加得过多
too much space in the file
占据文件系统
system.
太多的空间
So, let's have a look at the
好的 我们来看一看
starting implementation for this
这个 method 对应的
method.
起始实现
First, it asks for the set of
首先 它请求
all the current items in the
当前所有处在 cache 上的
cache, sorts them from newest to
条目集合
oldest.
按照从最新到最老的顺序排列
But then it [inaudible] over all
然后
of these items, keeping track of
这些条目
the total size of the items
记录下所有已见到条目
already seen.
的总大小
Once you've seen enough items
一旦你看到了
then we reached our maximum
达到了我们的最大容量
size, we begin removing the rest
的足够多的条目 我们就可以开始
of them from the file system.
将其余的从文件系统中移除出去了
So, let's think about how to
好的 让我们想想应该
test this method.
如何测试这个 method
What are the inputs?
什么是其 inputs
What are the outputs?
什么是其 outputs
Well, one input is the parameter
一个 input 是指定了
specifying how large you want
你想要 cache 最大能增大到多少的
the cache to be able to grow.
parameter
This is a simple integer, and a
这是一个简单的整数
method parameter, so the test
一个 method parameter
already has full control over
所以测试对其已经拥有
it.
完全的控制
The other input, is the list of
另外一个 input
items that are currently stored
是现在储存在 cache 上的
in the cache.
条目列表
We didn't take the time to look
我们就不去花时间看
at how this is implemented, but
这个到底是怎么实现的了
the key point is that it uses a
但是这里的关键是
file manager to retrieve a list
它使用了一个 file manage r来
of files from the disc.
从磁盘上取回一个文件列表
This means that the input is
这就意味着
actually derived from the file
input 实际是来源于
system, which is the dependency
文件系统的
that the tests would need to
测试则需要
deal with.
处理好这种依赖性
The clean cache method has no
clean cache method 没有
return value.
返回数值
So, its output can't be data.
所以 它的 output 不可能是数据
Rather, it's the side effect of
换句话说 它是
a certain set of files having
在一系列特定的文件被从磁盘移除后
been removed from the disc.
产生的副效应
Because of this dependency on
因为它依赖于文件系统
the file system, tests for this
对于这个 method 的测试
method would need to deal with a
就需要和在文件系统中的
file manager in the file system.
一个文件管理器打交道
For setup, they might need to
设置这些测试时
create a temporary directory and
可能需要它们创建一个临时文件夹
populate it with a bunch of
然后向其中填入一些
files of certain sizes and give
特定大小的文件
them particular timestamps to
并给它们加上特定的 timestamps
provide the input.
来提供 input
To validate the output, you
为了验证 output
would need to then return to the
你则需要随后返回到
file system to see which files
文件系统去看看哪些文件
are still there.
还在那里
One way to approach this could
一种实现该目的的方式
be to use the protocols and
就是使用
parameterization techniques that
我们之前看过的
we've already seen.
protocols 和 parameterization 技术
You could introduce a file
你可以引进一个
manager protocol that has the
文件管理器 protocol
methods that we need for getting
它具有我们需要的 methods
a list of files, and for
能够帮助我们得到一个文件列表
removing a file.
并移除一个文件
And then create a test
然后创建一个测试实现
implementation that would allow
能够详细列举
specifying the list of files
会被返回的
that would be returned, and a
文件列表
query of which ones have been
并针对哪些文件被移除
removed.
发出一个 query
If we do this though, we're
如果我们这么做
still interacting indirectly
我们还是在间接地
with the code that we're trying
同想要测试的代码互动
to test mediated by the file
文件管理器
manager.
负责居中进行协调
Instead, let's try something a
我们不这样做
little bit different.
来试试不同的方式
We could take our clean cache
我们可以使用
method and factor out the logic
clean cache method 并
responsible for deciding while
从负责确定哪些文件需要被移除的 logic 中
files should be removed, the
提出撰因子
clean-up policy, which you can
就是 clean-up policy
then interact with more
然后你就能够
directly.
进行更直接的互动了
Let's see how that might work.
我们来看看这个是如何运转的
To clearly define the APIs we're
为了清楚地界定我们
going to work with, let's first
要使用的 APIs
define clean-up policy as a
首先我们将 clean-up policy 定义为
protocol.
一个 protocol
It just needs a single method --
这只需要一个 method 即
items to remove.
itemsToRemove
Notice how the type signature
注意下我们给它加上的
that we've given it, looks a bit
type signature
different than from the clean
和之前我们开始时的
cache method that we started
clean cache method 的
with.
看起来有些不一样
As input, the new method takes a
作为 input
set of cache item values.
这个新的 method 使用一组 cache 条目数值
And for output, it returns
而对于 output
another set of them, but that is
它能够返回另一组数值
the ones to be removed.
但是这是那些将被移除的条目数值
So, let's see how we can
好的 我们就看看
implement this protocol using
如何用我们先前在
the algorithm that we previously
cache 类里面看到的算法
saw from the cache class.
来实现这个 protocol
Well, first define a property
好的 首先为 input 的最大值
for that max size input.
界定一个属性
That'll let us specify this max
这可以让我们明确这个最大的大小
size, and we construct the
然后我们可以构建
policy.
policy
Then we add the items to remove
然后我们添加
method that the protocol
protocol 要求的
requires.
itemsToRemove method
We want to inspect each of the
我们想要检查
items passed into the method,
每一个传递进 method 的条目
and build up a set of items to
然后构建一组将被移除的条目
remove, and return that to the
在完成之后
method when we're done.
再将其返回给 method
To populate the set, we'll loop
为了填充该组
over all of the items from
我们将这些条目按照从新至老的顺序
newest to oldest, summing up the
进行循环
size of all the items we've seen
计算已见所有条目大小
so far.
的总数
Once we've reached the maximum
一旦我们达到了最大值
size, we start adding the rest
就开始向这组 itemsToRemove
to the set of items to remove.
添加剩余的
Looking at this code, we can see
请看这条代码
that the side effects that were
我们能够发现在先前版本中
prone in the earlier version
容易出现的副效应
have been removed.
在此处已经被移除
What remains is the underlying
保留下来的是底层算法
algorithm, taking data as input,
将数据取作 input
and returning some data as
然后返回一些数据
output.
作为 output
We can also visualize the data
我们也可以将由此而
flow that we've achieved by
实现的数据流
doing this.
可视化
Notice that the code has taken
注意下 这个代码采用了
on a very functional style.
功能样式
Data in; data out.
数据进入 数据输出
With the logic factored out in
通过这种方式将 logic
this way, we've enabled
进行提出撰因子操作
ourselves to write clear,
我们能够写出清晰
concise tests that put the
简明的测试
algorithm through its paces.
然后对算法进行全面的测试
All we have to do is define an
我们需要做的就是界定
input set with some cache items,
包含有一些 cache 条目的输入集
create an instance of the type,
创建一个该类型的 instance
calling the method, directly
调用 method
passing in the values that it
直接将其需要的数值传递进入
needs, and then asserting that
然后判断
the returned items match the
返回的条目
expected result.
匹配预期的结果
With a code in this form, we now
有了这种形式的代码
have easy control over the
我们现在就能够轻易获得
inputs, visibility into the
对 inputs 的控制
outputs, and there's no hidden
及 outputs 的可视化显示
state to contend with at all.
没有任何需要进行处理的隐藏状态了
It's very reminiscent of the
这个特别能让我们
test for the sorted method that
联想到一开始看到的
we saw at the beginning.
为 sorted method 所写的测试
This allows the test to be easy
测试因此变得
to read, with minimal
极易读取
distraction from the essentials
测试要针对的要素
of what is being tested to run
也运行飞快
very quickly because it has no
受到的干扰也最小
dependency on slow resources
因为它不再需要依赖于运行速度慢的资源了
like the file system.
比如文件系统
And to be deterministic because
而且极具确定性
all of the data in use is fully
因为所有使用的数据
self-contained.
都是独立的
Taking a peek back at the
再回来看一眼
original clean cache method,
最初的 clean cache method
after the extraction, we see
我们发现在进行取出操作后
that there's very little left.
剩下的东西就不多了
All we're doing is asking the
我们现在只要请求
clean-up policy for the list of
clean-up policy 来
items to remove, and iterating
将条目移除
over all of them, removing them
然后迭代直到
from the file system.
将其全部移除出文件系统
To test what remains, we could
为了测试剩余的代码
decide to introduce that file
我们可以引进
manager protocol and testable
文件管理器 protocol 以及
implementation to allow writing
具备可测试性的实现
a very isolated unit tests for
来使得我们能够为其写一个
it.
十分独立的单元测试
Or we might decide that a couple
当然 我们也许也会觉得
of integration tests are
几个综合测试
sufficient to give the
就已经足够了
confidence that we need that the
就能够让我们对代码可以正确运行
code is doing the right thing.
有足够的把握
This thin layer of [inaudible]
这一薄薄的[听不清]
code that's left.
代码层就是剩下的
So, in this example, we looked
好的 在这个例子中
at how to extract business logic
我们看到了如何利用副效应
and algorithms into separate
将 business logic 和算法
types, away from the code, using
从代码中抽取出到
side effects.
单独的类型中
When doing this, the algorithms
在进行这种操作时
tend to take on a rather
算法通常会倾向于呈现功能样式
functional style, using value
使用数值类型
types to describe the inputs and
来描述 inputs
the outputs.
和 outputs
This allows for straightforward
这个使我们能够利用
unit tests that exercise the
简单直接的单元测试
algorithm in as much detail as
对算法进行测试
you require.
可以达到任何你所需的细致程度
We're left with a small amount
我们还剩下一小部分
of code that perform side
代码用来运行
effects based on the computer
基于电脑数据的
data.
副效应
This bit is often a good
这个部分经常
candidate for testing with
可以用综合测试
integration tests in order to
来进行很好的测试
track that its interaction with
这样就能够跟踪
the rest of the system is
它和余下的系统间的互动
working properly.
正在正常进行
So, to wrap up, we saw examples
总结一下
that allowed us to explore two
我们看过了一些例子
sets of techniques that allow us
这些例子能够帮助我们探索一些
to structure or ask code, so
允许我们构建或者请求代码的技术
that tests have control over the
这样测试就能够拥有对代码 inputs 的控制
code's inputs, and visibility
以及其 outputs 的可视性
into its outputs, thereby
因此 这就能够使我们
allowing us to write effective
为其写出
unit tests for it.
有效的单元测试
And now, I want to call up my
好的 现在我想要请我的同事上来
colleague, Greg Tracy, to talk
Greg Tracy 来给大家讲一讲
about how to create a test suite
如何创建能够随着你的 app
that scales with your app as it
成长也进行扩展的
grows.
测试套件
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Hi, everyone.
&gt;&gt; 大家好
My name is Greg.
我叫 Greg
And I also work on Xcode.
现在也在 Xcode 工作
Earlier, Brian showed you some
刚才 Brian 给大家展示了
techniques about how to make app
如何使得 app 代码更具可测试性
code more testable.
的一些技术
Now, I want to show you how to
现在我想要给大家展示
make the accompanying test code
如何使得伴随着的测试代码
more scalable.
更加具有可扩展性
To do this, we'll look at a few
为了达到这一点
methods to make tests faster,
我们会来一起看看几种能够让
more readable, and more
测试运行更快 更加易读 更模块化
modularized.
的方法
I also want to mention that many
我也想要提一下
of the techniques that Brian
刚才 Brian 所介绍的技术
described earlier, can also be
大多对测试代码
applied to test code.
也是适用的
Here, we're going to go through
不过在这里 我们会看看
some additional tips.
更多的小窍门
First, I'll talk about having a
首先 我会讲讲
balance between UI and unit
在 UI 和单元测试间达到一个平衡
tests.
这个话题
Then, dive into code that helps
然后 我会讲讲如何能够帮助测试
test scale with the focus on UI
具备可扩展性的代码
test code.
重点放在 UI 测试代码上
And then, I'll talk about the
随后 我会给大家说明
importance of having quality in
测试代码质量
test code.
的重要性
Striking the right balance
在 UI 测试和单元测试间
between UI and unit tests.
达到正确的平衡
I sometimes like to view my
有些时候 我喜欢
distribution of tests as a
将测试的分布视作
pyramid.
一个金字塔
At the top, you have your UI
最顶端的是 UI 测试
tests, and at the bottom, you
底部呢
have your unit tests.
则是单元测试
These [inaudible] pyramid
这个[听不清]
structure we usually have more
金字塔的结构也正好体现了现实情况
unit tests than we will UI
相较于 UI 测试而言
tests.
我们进行的单元测试数量会更多一些
This is usually because unit
这个通常是因为
tests can run much more quickly
单元测试的运行速度
than UI tests.
要比 UI 测试快很多
Now between UI and unit tests,
在 UI 测试和单元测试之间
we also have integration tests.
我们还有综合测试
However, today, we're going to
不过 今天我们会把重点
focus more on just UI and unit
放在 UI 测试
tests.
和单元测试上
Aside from the distribution, we
除了能够体现分布状态
might also look at the pyramid
这个金字塔结构
as a way to do maintenance
也能够体现不同测试的
costs.
维护成本
Generally, UI tests tend to have
一般情况下
a higher maintenance cost
UI 测试的维护成本会比较高
because of the number of things
因为会有各种各样的
that can happen.
情况发生
Unit tests on the other hand,
另一方面 单元测试
have a lower maintenance cost.
的维护成本则比较低
So, if a unit test fails, it's
所以 当一个单元测试失败后
usually immediately obvious
哪里出现了问题
what's gone wrong.
一般都是瞬间就一目了然的
With UI tests, it's like casting
而 UI 测试
a wide net where you can get
则像是撒下了一张大网
failures that are difficult to
可能能够捕捉到
understand, or might not be
难以理解的测试失败结果
relevant to the test at hand.
或者得到和手头测试相关性并不高的结果
So, it can be a bit more tricky.
所以 UI 测试可能会有些难以捉摸
While the testing pyramid is a
虽然这个金字塔结构
great way to represent
能够很好地展示
distributions of -- our
我们各种测试的分布状况
distribution of tests, it
但是并不能够
doesn't represent every
体现
situation.
每一种可能出现的情况
In fact, you might think of
事实上 你可以将测试
testing as a spectrum, rather
想象成为一个频谱
than a pyramid.
而非一个金字塔
It's often the case that some UI
一些 UI 测试和
and unit tests, exist on
单元测试 经常会存在于
opposite ends of the spectrum,
这个频谱的两端
or opposite ends of the pyramid.
或者是这个金字塔结构的两端
Some UI tests might be more like
一些 UI 测试可能会
unit tests, and a unit test
更像单元测试
might interact with several
而一个单元测试也可以
different modules of code and
和不同代码模块进行互动
not just single, isolated bits.
并不总是和单一独立的模块互动
The pyramid is just a good
只能说这个金字塔结构
approximation.
是最相近与真实情况的
It's not written in stone.
当然 它不可能是一成不变完全准确的
When thinking about these two
审视这两种
kinds of tests, we need to
不同测试的时候
consider each of their
我们需要考虑
strengths.
它们各自的优势
Unit tests are great at testing
单元测试很适合被用于测试
small bits of code that might be
一小部分代码
hard to reach without access to
而这部分代码可能在
all of our app source code.
无法访问我们 app 全部源码的情况下很难接触到
UI tests on the other hand, are
另一方面 UI 测试
great when you need to test
则在测试一大块代码
large chunks of code, working
同时运行的状况时
together.
表现出众
Of course, we need to keep in
当然了 我们还是要
mind that unit tests do have
时刻记住
access to all of our app's
单元测试能够访问到我们 app 的所有资源
source, whereas UI tests do not.
而 UI 测试则不可以
Focusing more on UI tests, let's
现在把重点放在 UI 测试上
look at a few things you could
我们来看看
to do improve the quality of
大家能够为提升自己测试代码质量
your test code.
采取哪些操作
By making some of the changes
采用我接下来建议的
I'm about to suggest, we can
一些变更
make it easier to create tests
我们能够轻松地创建
that scale alongside our app
可以随着我们 app 代码扩展的
code.
测试
We'll look at abstracting UI
我们讲如下几个方面
element queries, creating
抽象出 UI element queries
objects in utility functions,
在 utility functions 中创建 objects
which can then be placed in a
这个可以放在函数库中
library for later use, and
以后经常使用
utilizing keyboard shortcuts.
以及启用快捷键
So, first we'll look at
首先 我们来看看
abstracting UI element queries.
抽象出 UI element queries 这个方面
Say I have an app that has
比如说我有一个 app
several buttons in a view
在它的 view controller 中
controller.
有一些按钮
And each button is at the same
每一个按钮
level in the view hierarchy.
都处在相同的视图层级
The only difference is the name
唯一的区别
of each button.
就是每个按钮的名称不同
Instead of writing out this
与其把这个 query 写 7 次
query seven times, let's wrap
不如把它们一起放在
this up in a method.
一个 method 中
We can now modify each of our
现在我们就能够用
queries to use the new method we
刚刚创建好的新 method 来
just created.
修改每一个 query 了
However, I might even go
但是
further.
我还想要更进一步
Since each method calls the
既然每个 method 调用的对象
same, except for the name, let's
除去名字不同外 其它都一样
put all those names in array and
我们就把那些名字放在一个数组中
just loop through them.
然后对其进行循环即可
This adds some benefit of
这个方法有利于
maintainability for this code.
提高该代码的可维护性
If I add an extra button in the
如果我今后要添加
future, I don't have to add a
一个新按钮的话
new line of code.
我就不需要再添加一行新代码了
I just have to add an extra
我只需要向数组中
button name to the array.
多添加一个按钮的名字就可以了
By nature of what a UI test is,
由 UI 测试的性质决定
we're issuing a lot of these
我们会使用很多这样的
queries.
queries
So, if you're using the same
如果你要多次
query multiple times, store it
使用同一个 query
as a variable.
就最好将其储存起来作为一个 variable
Even if it's only part of a
即使只是一个 query 的一部分
query, store it somewhere.
也把它储存起来
Also, if you have queries that
同样的 如果你的 queries
are very similar, consider
都比较相似
creating a helper method around
则可以考虑围绕着 query
that query.
创建一个辅助方法(helper method)
The code will look a lot cleaner
代码就看起来整洁很多了
and become much more readable.
也会变得更加易读
In terms of scaling our test
就拓展我们的测试套件的角度说
suite, the use of shorter lines
使用更短的代码行
of code -- of shorter lines of
更短的测试代码行
test code and thoughtfully named
及细心命名的辅助方法
helper methods, will make it
可以在需要的时候
faster and easier to implement
更快速更简便地
new tests when the time comes.
施行新的测试
So, that was abstracting UI
这就是如何抽象出 UI element queries
element queries.
这一部分的内容
Now, let's move on to creating
现在我们继续下一个话题
objects in utility functions.
在utility functions 中创建 objects
I have this game I've been
我手头在做一款游戏
working on, and for each test, I
对于每一个测试
want to change some settings.
我都想要变更一些设置
Now, this is not a great example
我们现在看到的这个例子
of scalable code.
就不是一个很好的具有扩展性的代码
Because I've been recently
因为我最近
working with this app, I'm
一直都在和这个 app 打交道
familiar with how everything is
我自然很熟悉
laid out.
这个代码的里里外外
I understand exactly what's
我清楚的知道
going on.
所有正在发生的事情
However, later, if I was to come
但是 如果在一段时间后
back to this code after a few
比如几个星期后
weeks, or better yet, somebody
我再回头来看这个代码
not familiar with my code has to
或者另一个不熟悉我的代码的人
sit down and read what I wrote,
不得不坐下来读我写的这些代码的话
it might not make all that much
这些代码
sense.
就不一定能被很简单地读懂了
I first have to realize that I
首先我需要看出
have a Settings page that I need
我有一个 Settings 页面
to get in and out of.
我需要能够进入并离开这个页面
And I then have to realize that
然后我需要看出
between those two lines, I'm
在这两行之间
going through a difficulty page,
我有一个 difficulty 页
setting the difficulty, then I'm
设置 difficulty
going through a sound page, and
然后还有 sound 页
setting the sound.
设置 sound
Coming after an extended period
时间一旦过长
of time, I might not understand
我就可能会忘掉
why I have two back tabs at the
自己为什么会在底部
bottom.
有两个 back tabs
I would have to run through this
我必须使用测试
test to actually see this
来看看这个
happen.
代码到底会如何运行
And if the test were broken
如果因为实际 UI
because of some change in the
发生的变更
actual UI, I wouldn't be able to
而导致测试不成功
run my test, and I would be able
我就无法进行测试
to see what I wanted to see.
也就无法看到我想要的结果
I'd be clueless as to why the
这样 我基本上对当初
code was written the way it was.
为什么这样写这些代码这个问题无能为力了
To fix this, let's try to
为了解决这个问题
abstract away some of this logic
我们试一试将一些 logic 抽象到
into helper methods.
辅助方法里面
We can create a method to set
我们可以创建一个 method
the difficulty.
来设置 difficulty
And then similarly, we can
同样的
create a method to set the
我们也可以创建一个 method
sound.
来设置 sound
But can we do a little better?
不过 我们能够做的更好吗
Sure. We can instead, of instead
当然了
of passing stream typed
我们可以不传入 stream typed arguments
arguments, let's utilize enums.
转而使用 enums
That way, Xcode can -- helps
这样 Xcode 就能够
determine if the arguments we're
帮助我们在进行编译前确认
passing are even valid, before
正在传入的 arguments
we even compile.
是否是有效的
Now, looking at the code from
现在看一下我们先前的代码
before, if we replace some of
如果我们用新的辅助方法
the code with our new helper
代替一些代码
methods, we reduce what we had
我们就能够减少
before.
原来写的一些东西
And this is already starting to
这样已经看起来
look a lot better.
好多了
What about the initial jump in
那我们可以对最初的跳入跳出的
and out of the Settings page?
Settings 页面做些什么呢
Can we improve this as well?
我们能够对它进行改善吗
I think we can.
我觉得是可以的
Let's make a game app class.
让我们创建一个 GameApp 类
And in this class, I'll include
在这个类中
the enums I defined earlier for
我会加入之前为设定 difficulty 和sound
difficulty and sound.
界定好的 enums
I'll also include the helper
我也会加入
methods from before that set
之前用来配置那些设置的
those settings.
辅助方法
We'll create another method
我们创建另一个 method
called Configure Settings, that
叫做 configureSettings
takes the two settings as
它将之前的两个设置作为 inputs
inputs, and we'll migrate the
然后我们将之前的
setup logic from before, into
setup logic 移植进
the configure method.
configure method 里面
Back to where we were before,
回到我们先前的位置
now that we've created this game
因为我们已经创建了
app class, we can take away all
这 个GameApp 类
the code we wrote before, and
我们就可以拿走原来所写的全部代码了
just use a single call, the
然后只需要用一个调用即可
configure method.
也就是 configure method
This looks a lot more readable
相较于之前的版本
to me than what we had before.
这个对于我来说可读性要大多了
Now, if I wrote more tests than
现在 如果我需要写更多的测试
needed to set the settings, I
来配置设置
would just call our configure
我只需要调用
method.
configure method 就可以了
And if I needed to -- or if I
如果我需要
decided that I wanted to add
或者决定在 app 中
more settings to my app, I would
加入更多的设置
just have to update our
我只需要更新我们的
configure settings method to
configure settings method
handle these additional
就能够处理这些新添加的
settings.
设置了
From the example, one of the
从这个例子我们可以看出
most important things to do when
要扩展你的测试
trying to scale your tests, is
最重要的一点就是
to create abstraction that you
创建你能够随后放入
can later put into a library
library suite
suite.
的 abstraction
By doing this, we're
这样做
encapsulating common workflows
我们其实是在封装通用工作流程
that can be applied to more than
以将其适用在
one test.
多个测试上
This also means that we're able
这也意味着
to share test code across
我们能够将测试代码
different platforms.
分享到不同的平台上
And, of course, by sharing code,
当然了 分享代码
we improve maintainability.
能够便于我们的维护
If something related to an
如果出现了和抽象出的工作流程
abstracted workflow changes, we
相关的改动
only have to update our code in
我们只需要在一个地方更新代码即可
a single place, as opposed to
而不需要在
several.
多处都进行操作
One other improvement that I
我想要提一下另外一个改进
want to mention, in our
在我们的 configure method 中
configure method, and new in
因为今年 Xcode 进行了改进
Xcode this year, we can add an
我们可以
XCTContent.runActivity block to
在自己的代码中加入一个
our code.
XCTContent.runActivity
This makes it so that when we
当我们运行测试时
run our test, instead of having
我们可以用 runActivity 来
a log that contains all the
嵌套我们的 logging
actions that we made at the top
而不是得到一个
level, we can nest our logging,
包含所有顶层行为
using runActivity.
的 log
This helps organize our logging
这个能够帮助我们整理 logging
to make things look a little bit
可以让内容
cleaner.
看起来更加整洁一些
For more information regarding
有关测试 activity 特性的
the test activity feature, check
更多信息
out the earlier talk about
请查看我们先前的演讲
What's New in Testing?
What’s New in Testing
Now, let's move on to Utilizing
好的 现在我们继续下一个话题
Keyboard Shortcuts for macOS UI
如何对 macOS UI 测试
Tests.
使用快捷键
Let's say I have an app where
比如说我这里有一个 app
the user can pick a color for
用户能够为他们的 text
their text, using the standard
挑选颜色
macOS color picker.
使用的是标准 macOS color picker
And I'm writing a test to verify
我现在要写一个测试
that the color is set correctly.
来验证颜色都设置正确了
The typical way to bring up the
最典型的方式是在 app 中
color picker in my app is by
通过打开 Format menu
opening the Format menu, and
然后导航到 Font sub-menu
navigating to the Font sub-menu,
最后选择
and finally choosing Show
Show Colors
Colors.
来打开 color picker
I can write this in my UI test
我可以在 UI 测试中这样写
like this.
就像这样
But there's a faster way to do
但是有一种更快捷的方式
this that'll scale better as my
这个方式也能在我的测试[听不清]增多时
test [inaudible] grows.
更好地扩展
Notice that the Show Colors menu
注意这个 Show Colors menu 条目
item has an associated keyboard
有一个与其相关联的
shortcut.
键盘快捷方式了吧
Rather than using multiple lines
与其使用多行代码
of code to bring up the color
来启用 color picker
picker, we can just use one line
我们实际可以借助这个快捷键
of code using the shortcut.
只用一行代码就达到目的
And for the sake of readability,
出于可读性的考虑
I might use a wrapper to make
我也可能会使用一个 wrapper
this call for me.
来帮我调用
So, not only is this less code
这样 在我的测试中
to maintain in my tests, it's
不仅能够减少需要维护的代码数量
less code that has to be run
而且实际运行的代码也变少了
that isn't directly relevant to
那些和我想要进行的测试
the actual test I'm trying to
并不直接相关的代码
perform.
都被削减掉了
So, in an example test method, I
在之前测试 method 例子中
was previously going through the
我需要通过 menu
menu to get the color picker to
来最后显示出
show.
color picker
Using the new wrapper method, we
用这个新的 wrapper method
remove all those extra lines and
我们就去掉了这些多余的代码行
reduce to a single method.
将它精简到了一个 method
Not only does this make my test
这样不仅使我的测试
faster, it makes my code look a
运行得更快
lot more readable.
而且也提高了我的代码的可读性
Looking at what we just saw, if
我们刚才已经看到了
you're writing a UI test for a
如果你正在为一个 macOS 应用
macOS application, you can offer
写 UI 测试
a keyboard shortcut instead of
你可以直接提供一个键盘快捷键
going through the menu bar.
而不再需要通过 menu bar 来实现
I'm still going to have at least
我还需要
one test that ensures that
至少一个测试
bringing up the color picker via
来保证通过 menu bar 启用的 color picker
the menu bar, works properly,
能够正常运行
but that doesn't need to be
但是这不需要
repeated across every single
在每次包含 color picker
test that involves the color
的测试上
picker.
都重复运行
In the process of using keyboard
使用键盘快捷方式
shortcuts, we make our test code
我们可以通过
more compact by skipping extra
跳过一些 UI 中的步骤
steps needed to work through the
来使得测试代码
UI, sometimes reducing multiple
变得更加紧凑
lines of code to a single line,
有时可以将多行代码缩减到一行
which can help for readability.
这样也有助于提高代码可读性
Finally, I want to stress to all
最后 我想要对各位强调一点
of you that writing good tests
想要写出好的测试
is about writing good code.
其实就是要写出好的代码
It's easy to treat tests as an
大家很容易把测试
afterthought.
看成是马后炮 有些无关紧要
Usually, we focus on trying to
一般情况下
make our app the best it can
我们都十分看重 app 的制作 想将其做到最好
possibly be, by investing all
将所有的时间都投入到
this time in writing beautiful
写出优美的
app code that adheres to all
符合好的设计准则的
these principles of good design.
app 代码中去
We might have this additional
对于编写测试代码
requirement of writing test
我们也需要
code.
提高一点标准
It might be something tacked on
有可能你在最后一刻
at the end or done in a hurry
才匆忙挤出时间来写测试代码
just to check off a checkbox.
只是为了完成一项任务
But we can't allow this to
但是我们不应该
happen.
让这样的情况出现
Without the same attention to
如果不注意
detail, test code isn't going to
测试代码的细节
scale the same way our app code
它就无法像我们的 app 代码一样
might.
扩展下去
So, to that end, test code is
最后
important even though it isn't
测试代码虽然不是 shipping
shipping.
但仍然至关重要
Also note that the test suite
也请注意
should support the evolution of
测试套件理应能够帮助你的 app
your app, and not hinder change.
不断改进 而不是阻碍改变
With low quality test code, it
如果测试代码质量不高
becomes a burden to have to
每次你要对 app 做改动时
update your test whenever you
都需要更新测试
make a change to your app.
它就变成了你的负担
But by consciously designing
要有意识地
test code with quality in mind,
提高测试代码的质量
our ability to scale won't be
这样我们扩展的能力
inhibited by poorly designed
就不会因为设计不良的测试
tests.
而受到阻碍
And of course, coding principles
当然了
that apply to app code, also
编写 app 代码的原则
apply to test code.
也同样适用于编写测试代码
Test code and app code should be
测试代码和 app 代码
viewed equally.
应该被平等看待
And here's an idea for you.
这里我可以给大家出个主意
We should have code reviews for
我们需要对测试代码
test code, not just code reviews
进行代码审查
with test code.
而不仅仅是将测试代码用于代码审查
Having code reviews that are
要给测试代码
exclusively for test code,
进行单独的代码审查
ensures that somebody else is
保证是由别人来检查
checking your work, or
你的工作
and it's a chance to further
这也是改进测试本身
improve the tests themselves.
的一个机会
Now, I want to leave you with a
好的 现在我给大家留下
thought.
一个思路
App code and the tests that
app 代码以及
verify it, are really two halves
验证它的测试
of a whole.
其实是不可分割的两部分
When you update your app code,
当你更新 app 代码时
you'll need to update your test
你也需要
code too.
更新测试代码
We need to think of app code and
我们需要将 app 代码
the test code, as part of the
和测试代码视为同一件事的两部分
same thing, our code.
这个事情就是我们的代码
By making our code more
将我们的代码变得更
testable, as Brian discussed
具有可测试性 正如 Brian 先前和大家讨论的
earlier, and by treating test
用对待 app 代码同样认真的态度
code with the same care as your
对待测试代码
app code, you improve the
你就能够提升
quality of the whole app.
整个 app 的质量了
We ought to be proud of both
我们理应对
halves, and treat each with the
两部分都感到自豪
care and attention that they
并给予它们应得的
deserve.
关注
For more information and
有关这次讲座
resources regarding this
更多的信息和资源
session, you can visit the link
大家可以通过屏幕上的链接
listed on the screen.
获得
Here are a few related sessions.
这里有几个相关的讲座
One that happened yesterday, and
有一个是昨天的
a few that happened in previous
还有一些是前几年
years.
的讲座
You can check those out online,
大家可以上网查询
or through the WWDC app.
或者通过 WWDC app 查看
And with that, I'd like to thank
好了 谢谢大家的
you for your attention, and I
认真聆听
hope you enjoy the rest of the
我祝愿各位在剩下的时间里
conference.
与会愉快